

### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a UX-proficient sometimes-designer and most-of-the-time front-end developer. I'm passionate about design and enjoy the process of taking projects from simple ideas all the way through development. I like being challenged as well as the experience of learning new concepts when it comes to both design and development.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Northwestern University | Evanston, IL

B.A., Psychology

September 2011 - June 2015

#### CONTACT

w: nelsonchang.me

e: nelsonschang@gmail.com

t: 214 457 4466

#### SOCIAL

github.com/neldotpng

in linkedin.com/in/nelsonschang

## **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

### **Proficient**

HTML5 Git

CSS3 / SASS High-fi prototyping

JavaScript / ES6 Invision
Sketch GraphQL
React jQuery

React-Native

#### Intermediate

THREE.js Angular 4
WebGL D3.js

Dialogflow CoffeeScript Figma Hack / XHP

Webflow

# Basic / Exploring

Swift Webpack Unity Blender

Node

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## FREELANCER | Brooklyn, NY

### Design & Front End Development

June 2019 – Present

- Designed and developed a website for a non-profit organization using Webflow
- Contracted with Elephant NY to develop a high fidelity POC with React, as well as a high-fidelity React-Native prototype for user-testing
- Currently contracting with the New York Times' T-Brand Studio to develop interactive paid posts and contribute to an ongoing interactive atomic library

## TRUTH LABS (Perficient Digital Labs) | Chicago, IL

# Front End Engineer

June 2017 – May 2019

- · Paired with a back-end developer to develop interactive marketing sites
- Worked with other front-end developers to develop high-fidelity prototypes and POC's
- Experience working with new technologies and formats including Apple's USDZ file format for AR
- Contracted as a front-end developer for Facebook and gained experience working within a large codebase
- Completed a number of internal projects flexing 3D technologies like THREE.js and Unity
- Gained experience working with a number of development environments including React, React Native, Angular 4, Dialogflow, and VR.

## TRUNK CLUB | Chicago, IL

### Front End Designer

February 2016 – May 2017

- Sole front end developer for Trunk Club website rebrand and design overhaul
- · Completed 2 full site redesigns during my tenure
- Fleshed out a self-sustaining microsite for press releases as well as a gift card purchasing flow
- Worked with designers to rebrand and develop reusable templates for email marketing campaigns
- Developed reusable site templates using Statamic CMS
- · Designed and developed microinteractions and animations

### **DESIGNATION** | Chicago, IL

#### Designer-in-Residence

October 2015 - January 2016

- Led student stand-ups and advised students on project direction
- · Advised students on design direction and front-end development
- · Assisted with teaching efforts in the virtual phase of the program
- Designed and developed internal web pages with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript